<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMe 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
   <Article>
      <Journal>
         <PublisherName>BioMed Central</PublisherName>
         <JournalTitle>Hereditas</JournalTitle>
         <Issn>1601-5223</Issn>
         <Volume>160</Volume>
         <Issue>1</Issue>
         <PubDate PubStatus="ppublish">
            <Year>2023</Year>
            <Month>12</Month>
         </PubDate>
      </Journal>
      <Replaces>36907956</Replaces>
      <ArticleTitle>SMPD1 expression profile and mutation landscape help decipher genotype–phenotype association and precision diagnosis for acid sphingomyelinase deficiency</ArticleTitle>
      <FirstPage>11</FirstPage>
      <LastPage>11</LastPage>
      <Language>EN</Language>
      <AuthorList>
         <Author EqualContrib="Y">
            <FirstName>Ruisong</FirstName>
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <AffiliationInfo>
               <Affiliation>College of Life and Environmental Sciences, Hunan University of Arts and Science, 3150 Dongting Ave., Changde, 415000, Hunan Province, People’s Republic of China</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
               <Affiliation>Affiliated Hospital of Hunan University of Arts and Science (the Maternal and Child Health Hospital), Medical college, 3150 Dongting Ave., Changde, Hunan Province, People’s Republic of China, 415000</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
         </Author>
         <Author EqualContrib="Y">
            <FirstName>Ziyi</FirstName>
            <LastName>Qin</LastName>
            <AffiliationInfo>
               <Affiliation>College of Life and Environmental Sciences, Hunan University of Arts and Science, 3150 Dongting Ave., Changde, 415000, Hunan Province, People’s Republic of China</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
         </Author>
         <Author>
            <FirstName>Long</FirstName>
            <LastName>Huang</LastName>
            <AffiliationInfo>
               <Affiliation>College of Life and Environmental Sciences, Hunan University of Arts and Science, 3150 Dongting Ave., Changde, 415000, Hunan Province, People’s Republic of China</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
         </Author>
         <Author>
            <FirstName>Huiling</FirstName>
            <LastName>Luo</LastName>
            <AffiliationInfo>
               <Affiliation>College of Life and Environmental Sciences, Hunan University of Arts and Science, 3150 Dongting Ave., Changde, 415000, Hunan Province, People’s Republic of China</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
         </Author>
         <Author>
            <FirstName>Han</FirstName>
            <LastName>Peng</LastName>
            <AffiliationInfo>
               <Affiliation>College of Life and Environmental Sciences, Hunan University of Arts and Science, 3150 Dongting Ave., Changde, 415000, Hunan Province, People’s Republic of China</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
         </Author>
         <Author>
            <FirstName>Xinyu</FirstName>
            <LastName>Zhou</LastName>
            <AffiliationInfo>
               <Affiliation>College of Life and Environmental Sciences, Hunan University of Arts and Science, 3150 Dongting Ave., Changde, 415000, Hunan Province, People’s Republic of China</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
         </Author>
         <Author>
            <FirstName>Zhixiang</FirstName>
            <LastName>Zhao</LastName>
            <AffiliationInfo>
               <Affiliation>College of Life and Environmental Sciences, Hunan University of Arts and Science, 3150 Dongting Ave., Changde, 415000, Hunan Province, People’s Republic of China</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
         </Author>
         <Author>
            <FirstName>Mingyao</FirstName>
            <LastName>Liu</LastName>
            <AffiliationInfo>
               <Affiliation>College of Life and Environmental Sciences, Hunan University of Arts and Science, 3150 Dongting Ave., Changde, 415000, Hunan Province, People’s Republic of China</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
               <Affiliation>Changde Research Centre for Artificial Intelligence and Biomedicine, 3150 Dongting Ave., Changde, 415000, Hunan Province, People’s Republic of China</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
         </Author>
         <Author>
            <FirstName>Pinhong</FirstName>
            <LastName>Yang</LastName>
            <AffiliationInfo>
               <Affiliation>College of Life and Environmental Sciences, Hunan University of Arts and Science, 3150 Dongting Ave., Changde, 415000, Hunan Province, People’s Republic of China. pinhong_yang@163.com</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
               <Affiliation>Changde Research Centre for Artificial Intelligence and Biomedicine, 3150 Dongting Ave., Changde, 415000, Hunan Province, People’s Republic of China. pinhong_yang@163.com</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
         </Author>
         <Author>
            <FirstName>Tieliu</FirstName>
            <LastName>Shi</LastName>
            <AffiliationInfo>
               <Affiliation>College of Life and Environmental Sciences, Hunan University of Arts and Science, 3150 Dongting Ave., Changde, 415000, Hunan Province, People’s Republic of China. tieliushi@yahoo.com</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
               <Affiliation>Changde Research Centre for Artificial Intelligence and Biomedicine, 3150 Dongting Ave., Changde, 415000, Hunan Province, People’s Republic of China. tieliushi@yahoo.com</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
         </Author>
      </AuthorList>
      <ArticleIdList>
         <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41065-023-00272-1</ArticleId>
         <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s41065-023-00272-1</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <History>
         <PubDate PubStatus="received">
            <Year>2022</Year>
            <Month>10</Month>
            <Day>20</Day>
         </PubDate>
         <PubDate PubStatus="accepted">
            <Year>2023</Year>
            <Month>2</Month>
            <Day>28</Day>
         </PubDate>
         <PubDate PubStatus="aheadofprint">
            <Year>2023</Year>
            <Month>3</Month>
            <Day>13</Day>
         </PubDate>
      </History>
      <Abstract>
                BACKGROUND: 
                Acid sphingomyelinase deficiency (ASMD) disorder, also known as Niemann–Pick disease (NPD) is a rare genetic disease caused by mutations in SMPD1 gene, which encodes sphingomyelin phosphodiesterase (ASM). Except for liver and spleen enlargement and lung disease, two subtypes (Type A and B) of NDP have different onset times, survival times, ASM activities, and neurological abnormalities. To comprehensively explore NPD’s genotype-phenotype association and pathophysiological characteristics, we collected 144 NPD cases with strict quality control through literature mining.
              
                RESULTS: 
                The difference in ASM activity can differentiate NPD type A from other subtypes, with the ratio of ASM activity to the reference values being lower in type A (threshold 0.045 (4.45%)). Severe variations, such as deletion and insertion, can cause complete loss of ASM function, leading to type A, whereas relatively mild missense mutations generally result in type B. Among reported mutations, the p.Arg3AlafsX76 mutation is highly prevalent in the Chinese population, and the p.R608del mutation is common in Mediterranean countries. The expression profiles of SMPD1 from GTEx and single-cell RNA sequencing data of multiple fetal tissues showed that high expressions of SMPD1 can be observed in the liver, spleen, and brain tissues of adults and hepatoblasts, hematopoietic stem cells, STC2_TLX1-positive cells, mesothelial cells of the spleen, vascular endothelial cells of the cerebellum and the cerebrum of fetuses, indicating that SMPD1 dysfunction is highly likely to have a significant effect on the function of those cell types during development and the clinicians need pay attention to these organs or tissues as well during diagnosis. In addition, we also predicted 21 new pathogenic mutations in the SMPD1 gene that potentially cause the NPD, signifying that more rare cases will be detected with those mutations in SMPD1. Finally, we also analysed the function of the NPD type A cells following the extracellular milieu.
              
                CONCLUSIONS: 
                Our study is the first to elucidate the effects of SMPD1 mutation on cell types and at the tissue level, which provides new insights into the genotype-phenotype association and can help in the precise diagnosis of NPD.
              </Abstract>
      <CopyrightInformation>© 2023. The Author(s)</CopyrightInformation>
      <ObjectList>
         <Object Type="keyword">
            <Param Name="value">Acid sphingomyelinase deficiency</Param>
         </Object>
         <Object Type="keyword">
            <Param Name="value">Niemann-pick disease type a and B</Param>
         </Object>
         <Object Type="keyword">
            <Param Name="value">Genotype</Param>
         </Object>
         <Object Type="keyword">
            <Param Name="value">Phenotype</Param>
         </Object>
         <Object Type="keyword">
            <Param Name="value">Novel target for the subtypes</Param>
         </Object>
         <Object Type="grant">
            <Param Name="id">22YB13</Param>
            <Param Name="grantor">Hunan University of Arts and Science Research Project </Param>
         </Object>
         <Object Type="grant">
            <Param Name="id">22C0389</Param>
            <Param Name="grantor">Project of Hunan Provincial Department of Education</Param>
         </Object>
      </ObjectList>
      <ReferenceList>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Heller G, Bradbury AM, Sands MS, Bongarzone ER. Preclinical studies in Krabbe disease: a model for the investigation of novel combination therapies for lysosomal storage diseases. Mol Ther. 2023;31(1):7–23. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ymthe.2022.09.017
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ymthe.2022.09.017</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36196048</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Horowitz M, Braunstein H, Zimran A, Revel-Vilk S, Goker-Alpan O. Lysosomal functions and dysfunctions: molecular and cellular mechanisms underlying Gaucher disease and its association with Parkinson disease. Adv Drug Deliv Rev. 2022;187:114402. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1016/j.addr.2022.114402
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.addr.2022.114402</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35764179</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Kampine JP, Brady RO, Kanfer JN, Feld M, Shapiro D. Diagnosis of gaucher's disease and niemann-pick disease with small samples of venous blood. Science. 1967;155(3758):86–8. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1126/science.155.3758.86
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.155.3758.86</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6015567</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Martins AM, Valadares ER, Porta G, Coelho J, Semionato Filho J, Pianovski MA, et al. Recommendations on diagnosis, treatment, and monitoring for Gaucher disease. J Pediatr. 2009;155(4 Suppl):S10–8. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpeds.2009.07.004
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpeds.2009.07.004</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19765407</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Ron I, Horowitz M. ER retention and degradation as the molecular basis underlying Gaucher disease heterogeneity. Hum Mol Genet. 2005;14(16):2387–98. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1093/hmg/ddi240
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/hmg/ddi240</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16000318</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Sawkar AR, Cheng WC, Beutler E, Wong CH, Balch WE, Kelly JW. Chemical chaperones increase the cellular activity of N370S beta -glucosidase: a therapeutic strategy for Gaucher disease. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2002;99(24):15428–33. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.192582899
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.192582899</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12434014</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">137733</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Krabbe K. A new familial, infantile form of diffuse brain-sclerosis. Brain. 1916;39(1–2):74–114.</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/39.1-2.74</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Cesani M, Lorioli L, Grossi S, Amico G, Fumagalli F, Spiga I, et al. Mutation update of ARSA and PSAP genes causing metachromatic Leukodystrophy. Hum Mutat. 2016;37(1):16–27. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1002/humu.22919
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/humu.22919</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26462614</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Vanier MT. Niemann-pick disease type C. Orphanet J Rare Dis. 2010;5:16. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1186/1750-1172-5-16
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1750-1172-5-16</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20525256</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">2902432</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Schuchman EH, Desnick RJ. Types A and B Niemann-pick disease. Mol Genet Metab. 2017;120(1–2):27–33. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ymgme.2016.12.008
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ymgme.2016.12.008</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28164782</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Brady RO, Kanfer JN, Mock MB, Fredrickson DS. The metabolism of sphingomyelin. II. Evidence of an enzymatic deficiency in Niemann-pick diseae. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1966;55(2):366–9. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.55.2.366
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.55.2.366</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5220952</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">224150</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Vanier MT. Niemann–pick diseases. Handb Clin Neurol. 2013;113:1717–21.</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/B978-0-444-59565-2.00041-1</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23622394</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>de Frutos LL, Cebolla JJ, Irún P, Köhler R, Giraldo P. The erythrocyte osmotic resistance test as screening tool for cholesterol-related lysosomal storage diseases. Clin Chim Acta. 2018;480:161–5.</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cca.2018.02.010</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Greer WL, Riddell DC, Gillan TL, Girouard GS, Sparrow SM, Byers DM, et al. The Nova Scotia (type D) form of Niemann-pick disease is caused by a G3097→T Transversion in NPC1. Am J Hum Genet. 1998;63(1):52–4. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1086/301931
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/301931</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9634529</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">1377252</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Li G, Su B, Fu P, Bai Y, Ding G, Li D, et al. NPC1-regulated dynamic of clathrin-coated pits is essential for viral entry. Sci China Life Sci. 2022;65(2):341–61. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1007/s11427-021-1929-y
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11427-021-1929-y</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34047913</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Schuchman E, Desnick R. Niemann-pick disease types A and B: acid sphingomyelinase deficiencies. In: Scriver CR, Beaudet AL, Sly WS, Valle D, editors. The metabolic and molecular bases of inherited disease. New York: McGraw-Hill; 2001. p. 3589–610.</Citation>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Zhou Y-F, Metcalf MC, Garman SC, Edmunds T, Qiu H, Wei RR. Human acid sphingomyelinase structures provide insight to molecular basis of Niemann–pick disease. Nat Commun. 2016;7(1):13082. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1038/ncomms13082
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ncomms13082</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27725636</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">5062611</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Callahan JW, Jones CS, Davidson DJ, Shankaran P. The active site of lysosomal sphingomyelinase: evidence for the involvement of hydrophobic and ionic groups. J Neurosci Res. 1983;10(2):151–63. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1002/jnr.490100205
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jnr.490100205</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6313952</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Charruyer A, Grazide S, Bezombes C, Müller S, Laurent G, Jaffrézou JP. UV-C light induces raft-associated acid sphingomyelinase and JNK activation and translocation independently on a nuclear signal. J Biol Chem. 2005;280(19):19196–204. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1074/jbc.M412867200
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M412867200</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15769735</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Falcone S, Perrotta C, De Palma C, Pisconti A, Sciorati C, Capobianco A, et al. Activation of acid sphingomyelinase and its inhibition by the nitric oxide/cyclic guanosine 3′,5′-monophosphate pathway: key events in Escherichia coli-elicited apoptosis of dendritic cells. J Immunol. 2004;173(7):4452–63. 
                  https://doi.org/10.4049/jimmunol.173.7.4452
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4049/jimmunol.173.7.4452</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15383576</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Nasereddin A, Ereqat S. Deep sequencing of SMPD1 gene revealed a heterozygous frameshift mutation (p.Ser192Alafs) in a Palestinian infant with Niemann–pick disease type a: a case report. J Med Case Rep. 2018;12(1):272. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1186/s13256-018-1805-x
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13256-018-1805-x</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30223864</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">6142321</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Ota S, Noguchi A, Kondo D, Nakajima Y, Ito T, Arai H, et al. An early-onset Neuronopathic form of acid Sphingomyelinase deficiency: a SMPD1 p.C133Y mutation in the Saposin domain of acid Sphingomyelinase. Tohoku J Exp Med. 2020;250(1):5–11. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1620/tjem.250.5
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1620/tjem.250.5</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31941852</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Victor S, Coulter JBS, Besley GTN, Ellis I, Desnick RJ, Schuchman EH, et al. Niemann–pick disease: sixteen-year follow-up of allogeneic bone marrow transplantation in a type B variant. J Inherit Metab Dis. 2003;26(8):775–85. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1023/B:BOLI.0000009950.81514.c8
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/B:BOLI.0000009950.81514.c8</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14739682</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Coelho GR, Praciano AM, Rodrigues JP, Viana CF, Brandão KP, Valenca JT Jr, et al. Liver transplantation in patients with Niemann-pick disease--single-center experience. Transplant Proc. 2015;47(10):2929–31. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1016/j.transproceed.2015.10.051
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.transproceed.2015.10.051</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26707316</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Cheema HA, Rasool IG, Anjum MN, Zahoor MY. Mutational spectrum of SMPD1 gene in Pakistani Niemann-pick disease patients. Pak J Med Sci. 2020;36(3):479–84. 
                  https://doi.org/10.12669/pjms.36.3.467
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12669/pjms.36.3.467</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32292456</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">7150380</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Ordieres-Ortega L, Galeano-Valle F, Mallén-Pérez M, Muñoz-Delgado C, Apaza-Chavez JE, Menárguez-Palanca FJ, et al. Niemann-pick disease type-B: a unique case report with compound heterozygosity and complicated lipid management. BMC Med Genet. 2020;21(1):94. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1186/s12881-020-01027-9
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12881-020-01027-9</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32375665</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">7203852</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Li G, Eriani G, Wang ED, Zhou XL. Distinct pathogenic mechanisms of various RARS1 mutations in Pelizaeus-Merzbacher-like disease. Sci China Life Sci. 2021;64(10):1645–60. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1007/s11427-020-1838-2
                  
                . Epub 2021 Jan 28.</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11427-020-1838-2</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33515434</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Zhang X, Man Y, Zhuang X, Shen J, Zhang Y, Cui Y, et al. Plant multiscale networks: charting plant connectivity by multi-level analysis and imaging techniques. Sci China Life Sci. 2021;64(9):1392–422. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1007/s11427-020-1910-1
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11427-020-1910-1</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33974222</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Hu J, Maegawa GHB, Zhan X, Gao X, Wang Y, Xu F, et al. Clinical, biochemical, and genotype-phenotype correlations of 118 patients with Niemann-pick disease types A/B. Hum Mutat. 2021;42(5):614–25. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1002/humu.24192
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/humu.24192</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33675270</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Frazer J, Notin P, Dias M, Gomez A, Min JK, Brock K, et al. Disease variant prediction with deep generative models of evolutionary data. Nature. 2021;599(7883):91–5. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-021-04043-8
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-021-04043-8</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34707284</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Galehdari H, Tangestani R, Ghasemian S. New single nucleotide deletion in the SMPD1 gene causes Niemann pick disease type a in a child from Southwest Iran: a case report. Iran J Pediatr. 2013;23(2):233–6.</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23724191</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">3663321</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Irun P, Mallen M, Dominguez C, Rodriguez-Sureda V, Alvarez-Sala LA, Arslan N, et al. Identification of seven novel SMPD1 mutations causing Niemann-pick disease types A and B. Clin Genet. 2013;84(4):356–61. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1111/cge.12076
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cge.12076</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23252888</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Hashemian S, Eshraghi P, Dilaver N, Galehdari H, Shalbafan B, Vakili R, et al. Niemann-pick diseases: the largest Iranian cohort with genetic analysis. Iran J Child Neurol. 2019;13(2):155–62.</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31037088</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">6451857</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Zhang H, Wang Y, Gong Z, Li X, Qiu W, Han L, et al. Identification of a distinct mutation spectrum in the SMPD1 gene of Chinese patients with acid sphingomyelinase-deficient Niemann-pick disease. Orphanet J Rare Dis. 2013;8:15. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1186/1750-1172-8-15
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1750-1172-8-15</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23356216</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">3566977</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Rodriguez-Pascau L, Gort L, Schuchman EH, Vilageliu L, Grinberg D, Chabas A. Identification and characterization of SMPD1 mutations causing Niemann-pick types A and B in Spanish patients. Hum Mutat. 2009;30(7):1117–22. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1002/humu.21018
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/humu.21018</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19405096</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">2760245</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Pittis MG, Ricci V, Guerci VI, Marcais C, Ciana G, Dardis A, et al. Acid sphingomyelinase: identification of nine novel mutations among Italian Niemann pick type B patients and characterization of in vivo functional in-frame start codon. Hum Mutat. 2004;24(2):186–7. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1002/humu.9263
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/humu.9263</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15241805</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Sikora J, Pavlu-Pereira H, Elleder M, Roelofs H, Wevers RA. Seven novel acid sphingomyelinase gene mutations in Niemann-pick type a and B patients. Ann Hum Genet. 2003;67(Pt 1):63–70. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1469-1809.2003.00009.x
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1469-1809.2003.00009.x</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12556236</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Cao J, O’Day DR, Pliner HA, Kingsley PD, Deng M, Daza RM, et al. A human cell atlas of fetal gene expression. Science. 2020;370(6518):eaba7721. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1126/science.aba7721
                  
                .</Citation>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Carlyle BC, Kitchen RR, Kanyo JE, Voss EZ, Pletikos M, Sousa AMM, et al. A multiregional proteomic survey of the postnatal human brain. Nat Neurosci. 2017;20(12):1787–95. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1038/s41593-017-0011-2
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41593-017-0011-2</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29184206</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">5894337</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Kushner IK, Clair G, Purvine SO, Lee J-Y, Adkins JN, Payne SH. Individual variability of protein expression in human tissues. J Proteome Res. 2018;17(11):3914–22. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jproteome.8b00580
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jproteome.8b00580</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30300549</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Edelmann B, Bertsch U, Tchikov V, Winoto-Morbach S, Perrotta C, Jakob M, et al. Caspase-8 and caspase-7 sequentially mediate proteolytic activation of acid sphingomyelinase in TNF-R1 receptosomes. EMBO J. 2011;30(2):379–94. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1038/emboj.2010.326
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/emboj.2010.326</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21157428</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Jenkins RW, Canals D, Idkowiak-Baldys J, Simbari F, Roddy P, Perry DM, et al. Regulated secretion of acid sphingomyelinase: implications for selectivity of ceramide formation. J Biol Chem. 2010;285(46):35706–18. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1074/jbc.M110.125609
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M110.125609</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20807762</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">2975195</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Zeidan YH, Hannun YA. Activation of acid sphingomyelinase by protein kinase Cdelta-mediated phosphorylation. J Biol Chem. 2007;282(15):11549–61. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1074/jbc.M609424200
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M609424200</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17303575</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Jenkins RW, Idkowiak-Baldys J, Simbari F, Canals D, Roddy P, Riner CD, et al. A novel mechanism of lysosomal acid sphingomyelinase maturation: requirement for carboxyl-terminal proteolytic processing. J Biol Chem. 2011;286(5):3777–88. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1074/jbc.M110.155234
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M110.155234</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21098024</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Hurwitz R, Ferlinz K, Vielhaber G, Moczall H, Sandhoff K. Processing of human acid sphingomyelinase in normal and I-cell fibroblasts. J Biol Chem. 1994;269(7):5440–5.</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0021-9258(17)37705-0</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8106525</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Grassmé H, Gulbins E, Brenner B, Ferlinz K, Sandhoff K, Harzer K, et al. Acidic sphingomyelinase mediates entry of N. gonorrhoeae into nonphagocytic cells. Cell. 1997;91(5):605–15. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1016/s0092-8674(00)80448-1
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0092-8674(00)80448-1</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9393854</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Yuan Y, Li H, Pu W, Chen L, Guo D, Jiang H, et al. Cancer metabolism and tumor microenvironment: fostering each other? Sci China Life Sci. 2022;65(2):236–79. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1007/s11427-021-1999-2
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11427-021-1999-2</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34846643</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Oninla VO, Breiden B, Babalola JO, Sandhoff K. Acid sphingomyelinase activity is regulated by membrane lipids and facilitates cholesterol transfer by NPC2. J Lipid Res. 2014;55(12):2606–19. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1194/jlr.M054528
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1194/jlr.M054528</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25339683</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">4242453</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Mihaylova V, Hantke J, Sinigerska I, Cherninkova S, Raicheva M, Bouwer S, et al. Highly variable neural involvement in sphingomyelinase-deficient Niemann–pick disease caused by an ancestral gypsy mutation. Brain. 2007;130(4):1050–61. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awm026
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awm026</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17360762</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Dardis A, Zampieri S, Filocamo M, Burlina A, Bembi B, Gabriela PM. Functional in vitro characterization of 14 SMPD1 mutations identified in Italian patients affected by Niemann pick type B disease. Hum Mutat. 2005;26(2):164. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1002/humu.9353
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/humu.9353</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16010684</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Boustany R-M, Al-Shareef I, El-Haddad S. Chapter 104 - Sphingolipid disorders and the neuronal Ceroid Lipofuscinoses or batten disease (Wolman disease, Cholesteryl Ester storage disease, and Cerebrotendinous Xanthomatosis). In: Rimoin D, Pyeritz R, Korf B, editors. Emery and Rimoin's principles and practice of medical genetics. 6th ed. Oxford: Academic; 2013. p. 1–85.</Citation>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Desnick JP, Kim J, He X, Wasserstein MP, Simonaro CM, Schuchman EH. Identification and characterization of eight novel SMPD1 mutations causing types A and B Niemann-pick disease. Mol Med. 2010;16(7–8):316–21. 
                  https://doi.org/10.2119/molmed.2010.00017
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2119/molmed.2010.00017</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20386867</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">2896470</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Mukherjee SB, Pandey M, Kapoor S, Priya TP. Infant with type a Niemann pick disease and undetectable Niemann pick cells in bone marrow. Indian Pediatr. 2012;49(6):490–2. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1007/s13312-012-0095-4
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13312-012-0095-4</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22796693</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Graber D, Salvayre R, Levade T. Accurate differentiation of neuronopathic and nonneuronopathic forms of Niemann-pick disease by evaluation of the effective residual lysosomal sphingomyelinase activity in intact cells. J Neurochem. 1994;63(3):1060–8. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1471-4159.1994.63031060.x
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1471-4159.1994.63031060.x</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8051547</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Ding Y, Li X, Liu Y, Hua Y, Song J, Wang L, et al. Seven novel mutations of the SMPD1 gene in four Chinese patients with Niemann-pick disease type a and prenatal diagnosis for four fetuses. Eur J Med Genet. 2016;59(4):263–8. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejmg.2015.11.012
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejmg.2015.11.012</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26851525</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Al-Eitan L, Alqa'qa K, Amayreh W, Aljamal H, Khasawneh R, Al-Zoubi B, et al. Novel mutations in the SMPD1 gene in Jordanian children with acid sphingomyelinase deficiency (Niemann-pick types A and B). Gene. 2020;747:144683. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gene.2020.144683
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gene.2020.144683</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32311413</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Pavlů-Pereira H, Asfaw B, Poupctová H, Ledvinová J, Sikora J, Vanier MT, et al. Acid sphingomyelinase deficiency. Phenotype variability with prevalence of intermediate phenotype in a series of twenty-five Czech and Slovak patients. A multi-approach study. J Inherit Metab Dis. 2005;28(2):203–27. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1007/s10545-005-5671-5
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10545-005-5671-5</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15877209</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>McGovern MM, Dionisi-Vici C, Giugliani R, Hwu P, Lidove O, Lukacs Z, et al. Consensus recommendation for a diagnostic guideline for acid sphingomyelinase deficiency. Genet Med. 2017;19(9):967–74. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1038/gim.2017.7
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/gim.2017.7</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28406489</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">5589980</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Lipinski P, Kuchar L, Zakharova EY, Baydakova GV, Lugowska A, Tylki-Szymanska A. Chronic visceral acid sphingomyelinase deficiency (Niemann-pick disease type B) in 16 polish patients: long-term follow-up. Orphanet J Rare Dis. 2019;14(1):55. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1186/s13023-019-1029-1
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13023-019-1029-1</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30795770</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">6387484</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Ricci V, Stroppiano M, Corsolini F, Di Rocco M, Parenti G, Regis S, et al. Screening of 25 Italian patients with Niemann-pick a reveals fourteen new mutations, one common and thirteen private, in SMPD1. Hum Mutat. 2004;24(1):105.</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/humu.9258</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15221801</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Zampieri S, Filocamo M, Pianta A, Lualdi S, Gort L, Coll MJ, et al. SMPD1 mutation update: database and comprehensive analysis of published and novel variants. Hum Mutat. 2016;37(2):139–47.</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/humu.22923</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26499107</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Fernández-Burriel M, Peña L, Ramos JC, Cabrera JC, Marti M, Rodríguez-Quiñones F, et al. The R608del mutation in the acid sphingomyelinase gene (SMPD1) is the most prevalent among patients from gran Canaria Island with Niemann-pick disease type B. Clin Genet. 2003;63(3):235–6. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1034/j.1399-0004.2003.00025.x
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1034/j.1399-0004.2003.00025.x</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12694237</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Liu J, Li J, Wang H, Yan J. Application of deep learning in genomics. Sci China (Life Sciences). 2020;v.63(12):92–110.</Citation>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Ponting CP. Acid sphingomyelinase possesses a domain homologous to its activator proteins: saposins B and D. Protein Sci. 1994;3(2):359–61. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1002/pro.5560030219
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pro.5560030219</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8003971</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">2142785</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Munford RS, Sheppard PO, O'Hara PJ. Saposin-like proteins (SAPLIP) carry out diverse functions on a common backbone structure. J Lipid Res. 1995;36(8):1653–63.</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0022-2275(20)41485-3</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7595087</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Hollak CE, de Sonnaville ES, Cassiman D, Linthorst GE, Groener JE, Morava E, et al. Acid sphingomyelinase (Asm) deficiency patients in the Netherlands and Belgium: disease spectrum and natural course in attenuated patients. Mol Genet Metab. 2012;107(3):526–33. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ymgme.2012.06.015
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ymgme.2012.06.015</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22818240</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Huang L, Khusnutdinova A, Nocek B, Brown G, Xu X, Cui H, et al. A family of metal-dependent phosphatases implicated in metabolite damage-control. Nat Chem Biol. 2016;12(8):621–7. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1038/nchembio.2108
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nchembio.2108</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27322068</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">7001580</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Thurberg BL. Autopsy pathology of infantile neurovisceral ASMD (Niemann-pick disease type a): Clinicopathologic correlations of a case report. Mol Genet Metab Rep. 2020;24:100626. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ymgmr.2020.100626
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ymgmr.2020.100626</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32714837</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">7371898</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Grafft CA, Fervenza FC, Semret MH, Orloff S, Sethi S. Renal involvement in Neimann-pick disease. NDT Plus. 2009;2(6):448–51. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1093/ndtplus/sfp101
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ndtplus/sfp101</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25949377</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">4421332</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Jerbi M, Sayhi M, Gaied H, Hedri H, Aoudia R, Goucha R, et al. Renal Thrombotique microangiopathy: an unusual renal involvement in Niemann-pick disease type B. Clinical Case Rep. 2020;8(12):3315–20. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1002/ccr3.3408
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ccr3.3408</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Li G, Li X, Zhuang S, Wang L, Zhu Y, Chen Y, et al. Gene editing and its applications in biomedicine. Sci China Life Sci. 2022;65(4):660–700. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1007/s11427-021-2057-0
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11427-021-2057-0</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35235150</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">8889061</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Tierney AL, Nelson CA 3rd. Brain development and the role of experience in the early years. Zero Three. 2009;30(2):9–13.</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23894221</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">3722610</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Tirelli C, Arbustini E, Meloni F. Bilateral cystic bronchiectasis as novel phenotype of Niemann-pick disease type B successfully treated with double lung transplantation. Chest. 2021;159(5):e293–e7. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chest.2020.11.074
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chest.2020.11.074</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33965151</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Wang H, Yi Z, Shi T. Novel loci and potential mechanisms of major depressive disorder, bipolar disorder, and schizophrenia. Sci China Life Sci. 2022;65(1):167–83. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1007/s11427-020-1934-x
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11427-020-1934-x</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34159505</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Wu SY, Wang H, Shao ZM, Jiang YZ. Triple-negative breast cancer: new treatment strategies in the era of precision medicine. Sci China Life Sci. 2021;64(3):372–88. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1007/s11427-020-1714-8
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11427-020-1714-8</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32803712</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Carsana EV, Lunghi G, Prioni S, Mauri L, Loberto N, Prinetti A, et al. Massive accumulation of Sphingomyelin affects the Lysosomal and mitochondria compartments and promotes apoptosis in Niemann-pick disease type a. J Mol Neurosci. 2022;72(7):1482–99. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1007/s12031-022-02036-4
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12031-022-02036-4</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35727525</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">9293875</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Wang D, Eraslan B, Wieland T, Hallström B, Hopf T, Zolg DP, et al. A deep proteome and transcriptome abundance atlas of 29 healthy human tissues. Mol Syst Biol. 2019;15(2):e8503.</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15252/msb.20188503</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30777892</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">6379049</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Papatheodorou I, Moreno P, Manning J, Fuentes AM-P, George N, Fexova S, et al. Expression atlas update: from tissues to single cells. Nucleic Acids Res. 2019;48(D1):D77–83. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1093/nar/gkz947
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkz947</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">7145605</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Wilhelm M, Schlegl J, Hahne H, Gholami AM, Lieberenz M, Savitski MM, et al. Mass-spectrometry-based draft of the human proteome. Nature. 2014;509(7502):582–7. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1038/nature13319
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature13319</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24870543</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Samaras P, Schmidt T, Frejno M, Gessulat S, Reinecke M, Jarzab A, et al. ProteomicsDB: a multi-omics and multi-organism resource for life science research. Nucleic Acids Res. 2019;48(D1):D1153–D63. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1093/nar/gkz974
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkz974</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">7145565</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Schmidt T, Samaras P, Frejno M, Gessulat S, Barnert M, Kienegger H, et al. ProteomicsDB. Nucleic Acids Res. 2017;46(D1):D1271–D81. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1093/nar/gkx1029
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkx1029</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">5753189</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Wang K, Li M, Hakonarson H. ANNOVAR: functional annotation of genetic variants from high-throughput sequencing data. Nucleic Acids Res. 2010;38(16):e164-e.</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkq603</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Robinson MD, McCarthy DJ, Smyth GK. edgeR: a bioconductor package for differential expression analysis of digital gene expression data. Bioinformatics. 2010;26(1):139–40. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1093/bioinformatics/btp616
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bioinformatics/btp616</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19910308</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
         <Reference>
            <Citation>Yu G, Wang LG, Han Y, He QY. clusterProfiler: an R package for comparing biological themes among gene clusters. Omics. 2012;16(5):284–7. 
                  https://doi.org/10.1089/omi.2011.0118
                  
                .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
               <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/omi.2011.0118</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22455463</ArticleId>
               <ArticleId IdType="pmcid">3339379</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
         </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
   </Article>
</ArticleSet>
